Color is relative!
And that is the one rule that you really need to remember.
Every time you change a color, in a painting you change everything else that is happening around it.
This is just a very simple test.
This color looks sort of like a blue pink.
This looks kind of like a orange corral pink.
These are in fact the same pink.
Let me prove it.
The same pink!
I cut them off out, off of the same stripe.
But in a different ground, this pink looks different.
That means that you've got an awful lot of color testing in front of you.
I'm just going to show you again a dark pink here.
And again the same thing happens.
This is looking more purple.
This is looking very purple actually.
And this again looks more orange.
This is, happens something to do A with the fact that the colors are mixed.
I mean the blue is straight out of the jar as is the red.
The pink I had to mix.
Now I mixed the pink with white.
You know got to get it lighter.
And I put in a little blue.
What happens is, the red sucks up all the colors in the light spectrum except red.
Then you've got this on top, and it's going to respond more blue.
On the blue where every color but blue is being sucked up.
Then this responds differently.
There is sort of no more blue, so it becomes more on the orange side.
So weather it's a dark or a light color, the fact that it's a mixed color, when it's next to something different.
Again I'm going to move this down here.
That's the same color.
But you wouldn't think it to look up here.
So that's the foot of the very basic idea behind color adjust position.